(QUIET MUSIC PLAYING)
(GRAND MUSIC PLAYING)
(WHIMSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
FRONT GATE BARKER:
Hurry, hurry, step this way.
Get your tickets now.
Don't be shut out, friend.
Step this way.
See the most
wondrous sights imaginable
pulled from the four corners
of the Earth.
Acts to delight,
to thrill and to mystify!
Walk through these gates
and into a world of wonder!
(MAN GRUNTING)
She is here, ladies and gents,
live and in person.
That gun-slinging, sharp-shooting
honey-pie of the Wild West.
He has traveled the world and
baffled the crown princes of Europe.
-He will amaze! He will astound !
-(CROWD GASPS)
The Great and Powerful Oz!
I always knew that I was
destined for show business.
And now look at me.
A magician's assistant.
To think,
an hour ago I was just
selling oil cakes
on the midway.
OZ: Yes, well,
opportunity comes
when you least expect it,
my dear.
(MAY GASPS)
Wow! What a get-up.
-You won't need this.
-Oh.
You are playing
the simple country girl.
(GASPS) Oh !
(CHUCKLING)
A gift in honor
of your debut.
Oh !
Now, this belonged to
my grandmother.
A tsarina from Mirkutsk,
and a decorated war hero.
Your grandmother?
Yes. She was killed in battle,
the poor thing.
Which battle?
-Which battle?
-Uh-huh.
Well, there are so many.
You've heard
of the Battle of Kreplach?
No.
No? Good.
That's where she died.
And this music box
was the only thing to survive.
(QUIET MUSIC PLAYING)
(GASPS)
But I know that Grammie
would want you to have it.
-(DOOR OPENS)
-Professor.
Frank!
The sock is on the door.
We're rehearsing.
How many times do
I have to tell you to knock?
Knock.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
I knocked.
-What is it?
-Showtime.
Why didn't you say something?
Only a half a house.
Here's the take.
Pitiful.
All right,
this is your cut.
For you, the applause
will be approbation enough.
(MAY LAUGHS)
Well, how do you think I feel?
A man of my talents,
I should be playing
the Orpheum Circuit!
Instead of some
dusty podunk
in a second-hand jacket
falling apart at the seams.
You're gonna have to patch
this thing again.
-Again?
-Yeah.
-Let's go. Hat!
-(BLOWS)
-Hat.
-MAY: Hat. Okay.
-You're the new girl, huh?
-Yes.
Good, we needed a new one.
The last one left us.
Poor thing.
Suffered from a broken heart.
Attack. Heart attack.
But she's resting comfortably
now in Abilene
expected to
make a full recovery.
Perhaps you'd
like to join her.
Now, remember,
when I ask for a volunteer. . .
I raise my hand.
(LAUGHS)
You are overqualified
for this job, my dear.
Let's go make some magic.
SIDESHOW BARKER:
Ladies and gentlemen,
the show has already begun.
There are still
a few seats left.
Don't miss your chance to see
Oz, the Great and Powerful !
OZ: Journey with me now,
across those deserts
to the mystical lands
of the Arabian Peninsula.
(PIANO PLAYING
MYSTERIOUS MUSIC)
(SCATTERED APPLAUSE)
For 5,000 years,
her lonely spirit
has been trapped.
But tonight,
we will attempt to free her.
I shall require a volunteer
from the audience.
Anyone.
How about you, madam?
Oh ! Yes, I would
like to volunteer.
(LAUGHS HUMORLESSLY)
How kind of you. Please.
(SOFTLY)
Just remember what I told you.
A simple country girl,
ladies and gentlemen.
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDS)
Now, you have nothing to fear,
just so long as you believe.
For when you do believe
anything is possible.
(BLOWING)
You are growing sleepy.
Your eyelids become heavy.
Sleep!
Come, Fernanda!
(DRUM ROLL)
(AUDIENCE GASPING)
Allow yourself to merge
with this woman before me.
(AUDIENCE GASPING)
Can you hear me,
oh, Queen Fernanda?
(HOARSELY) Yes.
(EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
Then rise.
Rise!
(GASPS)
I command you to rise!
(BLOWING PIPES)
Rise from your tomb of sand.
(AUDIENCE GASPING)
Rise as your spirit. . .
I see a wire!
You are mistaken, sir.
I am not!
There is a wire!
There is a wire
holding her up!
A wire?
I see it, too.
It's right there.
(AUDIENCE GRUMBLING)
MAN 1 : Clear as day.
Can't you see 'em?
MAN 2: He's fooling us.
A wire!
What need have I of wires?
Frank.
(DRUM ROLL)
(CYMBALS CRASH)
(GASPING)
(APPLAUSE)
Make me walk!
What's that?
Make me walk.
Not now, kid. Let us leave the wonders. . .
But I believe in you.
Look, it's not much,
but it's all that we have.
Whatever you could do.
I would make you walk,
it's just. . .
It's just that. . .
MAN 1 : Well, go on, then.
Make the girl walk.
Make the kid walk.
MAN 2: Come on, you big phony.
BOY: Yeah, come on !
I would make her walk,
of course,
but unfortunately there
is a distemper in the ether tonight.
Make the kid walk,
you big phony.
You see?
(SOBBING)
I'm sorry, but. . .
(AUDIENCE JEERING)
Thank you. Thank you.
Oz, the Great and Powerful.
Why didn't you close
the damn curtain sooner?
I was dying out there.
There was nothing
you could have done.
I didn't really think
it was that bad.
Of course not.
You're just a trained monkey.
You know, you shouldn't
be so mean to me all the time, Professor.
After all,
I'm the only friend you've got.
Friend?
You're not my friend, Frank.
I don't need a friend.
What I need is someone who knows
when to close the damn curtain.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
It's a woman.
Ah ! Finally some good news.
You want me to
wind up a music box?
No.
Not for this one, Frank.
Hey, Annie.
Hello, Oscar.
Hmm.
You look lovely.
Thank you.
What is this? Gingham?
(CHUCKLES)
You know it is.
It was a wonderful show.
Oh, don't tell me
you watched that debacle.
I don't know why you didn't
just tell that poor girl the truth.
What truth? That I'm a fake?
They would have had my head.
And worse, they would have
demanded a refund.
Come on, have a seat.
I'll get you some tea.
-(THUMPING)
-Ooh !
(OZ CHUCKLES)
It's been a long time.
I haven't seen you since. . .
The last time you
rolled into town.
It's not often enough, Oscar, seeing you
once every few months.
(SIGHS) Well,
it is a traveling circus.
How's everything on the farm?
How's your ma?
She didn't send me
a pie this time.
I hope she's not mad.
I meant to write.
I need to tell you
something, Oscar.
That's never a good start
to a conversation.
John Gale asked me
to marry him.
That's why I've come.
I thought you should know.
Oh.
I think that's. . .
That's wonderful, Annie.
I said I had
to think about it.
(CHUCKLES HUMORLESSLY)
Oh, men love that answer.
I wondered what you
thought I should do.
You could do a lot worse
than John Gale.
He's a good man.
ANNIE: So are you.
OZ: No.
I'm not.
I'm many things,
but a good man is not one of them.
But you could be.
(SIGHS)
If you wanted to.
Well, that's just it.
I don't want to.
See, Kansas is full
of good men.
Church-going men that get
married and raise families.
Men like John Gale.
Men like my father,
who spent his whole
life tilling the dirt
just to die facedown in it.
I don't want that, Annie.
I don't want to be a good man,
I want to be a great one.
I want to be Harry Houdini
and Thomas Edison
all rolled into one.
That's all I ever
wanted for you, you know.
Greatness.
Then you understand.
I do.
But do you?
Uh, Professor, you need
to look outside.
No, Vlad, please.
It was his grandmother's.
-(GRUNTS)
-Ah !
I'm gonna rip him in half!
(GRUNTING)
-No, please!
-Get off!
It was just his
grandmother's music box.
It meant nothing.
VLAD: Oz!
I have to go.
Congratulations on
the engagement.
Oscar.
I'll see you in my dreams.
-(VLAD YELLS)
-(SCREAMS)
VLAD: Oz!
I'm gonna rip your head off!
Zim Zallah Bim !
Oz!
There he is!
He's out here!
No, Vlad ! Don't hurt him !
Vlad !
-Vlad, no!
-Whoa!
I'm gonna crush you, Oz!
(GRUNTING)
I'm gonna crush you !
BAUM: Oz! Where are you going?
Mr. Baum, I'll catch up
with you in Milwaukee.
Half of that balloon is mine!
OZ: And the other half
is mine!
BAUM: All right, you loafers!
Roll up those tents!
(OZ PANTING)
-(LAUGHS)
-(GRUNTS)
Oz!
-No, no, no.
-You're not getting away!
OZ: Where's my thing?
Come here.
Get him down, Clowny.
No, you don't!
Oh, no, you don't!
(LAUGHS MANIACALLY)
Ah !
(LAUGHS TRIUMPHANTLY)
OZ: So long, sucker!
Get back here!
FRANK: Oz!
Oz, you're gonna need these!
OZ: Throw it! Now!
-Hat!
Ha-ha!
You're a dead man !
Farewell !
Au revoir! Auf Wiedersehen!
-(CROWD SHOUTING)
-VLAD: Run !
Run !
(GASPING)
No, no, no, no, no! No!
(SCREAMING)
Whoa!
(YELLING)
(PANTING)
(SCREAMING)
(GASPING)
Please, I don't wanna die!
I haven't
accomplished anything yet!
Just get me out of here
and I'll do great things!
Please! Give me a chance!
I promise!
I promise. I can change.
(NOISE DIES DOWN)
(ORGAN PLAYING TUNE)
(GASPS)
(WIND WHISTLING)
(EXHALES)
Thank you. Thank you !
(SCREAMING)
Come on, come on !
Oh, no!
(CONTINUES SCREAMING)
(TWITTERING)
(BELLS RINGING)
(CHIMES TINKLING)
(CHIMING)
(STRUMMING MUSICALLY)
(BLOWING TUNEFULLY)
(BUBBLING)
No, no. No, no.
Come on, buddy.
I can't swim.
No! I can't swim.
(GASPING)
Somebody, help me!
(HOOTING)
Thank goodness.
I thought I was dead.
Unless you're an angel.
Am I in heaven?
(LAUGHING)
There is still hope for me!
You won't regret this!
I saw you fall from the sky.
Oh. Uh. . . Yes, my balloon
hit, uh, an inverted thermal.
I couldn't compensate.
WOMAN: I'd get out
of the water if I were you.
Oh. It's actually quite nice.
I'd be more concerned
with the River Fairies.
Their teeth are small,
but very sharp.
River Fairies? (CHUCKLES)
What's a River Fairy?
-(CHOMPING SOUND)
-Ow!
Ow! Get off!
Ow! Ow!
(WHISTLING TUNEFULLY)
Psst. Psst.
Go on, get out of here.
(WHISTLING TUNEFULLY)
(CHITTERING)
Spiteful little things,
aren't they?
Where. . .
Where am I, exactly?
Where do you think you are?
I have no idea. It's. . .
It's like no place
I've ever seen.
You're in Oz.
Oz?
But that's my name.
Oscar Zoroaster
Phadrig Isaac Norman
Henkle Emmanuel
Ambroise Diggs.
But everyone calls me Oz.
I knew it!
The king's prophecy was true.
He said that a great wizard
bearing the name of our land
will descend
from the heavens, and save us all.
And here you are.
Here to claim your throne.
"Claim my throne"?
You mean,
like a king's throne?
Well, yes. Because
you will be our king.
Your king?
Like, in a palace with
a crown and a scepter?
Yes, a beautiful scepter
and a grand palace.
Oh. And you will
save all the people.
Was that a gold scepter?
Yes, there's more gold
than you could ever imagine.
And Oz will now be
what it once was.
Because you are
the Wizard, aren't you?
Yes.
I'm the Wizard.
(CHUCKLES)
-(LOUD SHRIEKING)
-(GROWLING)
-What was that?
-The Wicked Witch's minions.
They've been sent here
to kill you.
Kill me?
A wicked witch? What?
-(LOUD GROWLING)
-Oh !
We better hurry or your reign will be
over before it's begun !
-Whoa!
-OZ: Oh ! Whoa!
-Oh !
OZ: Come on !
In there!
Give me your leg.
-(CREATURE GROWLING)
-Huh?
(CREATURE GRUNTING)
(FOOTSTEPS THUMPING)
Oh. . . Perhaps the Wicked Witch
has summoned them back.
I don't think
I like witches.
(CHUCKLING)
What?
I. . . I, too,
am a witch.
I am Theodora the Good.
(LAUGHS)
You're not a witch.
Of course I am.
Where are all your warts?
Where's your broom?
What would I do with a broom?
Fly.
With a broom?
Never mind.
-(LOUD THUMP)
-(BOTH GASPING)
(CREATURE SNARLING)
(GASPING)
You were afraid?
Yes.
That something
might happen to you.
OZ: So, this Wicked Witch,
just how wicked is she?
THEODORA:
She's as wicked as they come.
She poisoned her own father.
That's pretty wicked.
He was a king
and a wizard, like you.
But she wanted the throne
all to herself.
Poor man.
But my sister chased her away
from the Emerald City.
I can't wait
for her to meet you.
She was starting to doubt you'd ever
come but now she'll see.
And you're going to
fix everything.
Yeah.
You know what
I think we need?
A little music.
Is that magic?
In a way.
It's a music box.
You've never seen one?
Well, this belonged to
my grandmother.
A tsarina from Mirkutsk.
(QUIET MUSIC PLAYING)
Go on.
I want you to have it.
No one's ever given me anything
just because they wanted to.
A pretty girl like you?
With the visage
of Helen of Troy, no less?
I'm sure you have
dozens of admirers.
You don't know much
about witches, do you?
Maybe not, but I'm told
I'm a fast learner.
May I have this dance, milady?
Now you're gonna tell me no one's ever
asked you to dance before.
No one ever has.
Then it's high time
that you learned.
Put your hand here.
And your other hand here.
Nice, isn't it?
Yes.
It's incredible.
Yeah.
Here I thought
I'd live a lonely life
and then you showed up.
(SIGHS)
Not only are you
the Wizard
but you're the person
I belong with.
Well, we sure
get along. And. . .
And?
And,
like you said,
we belong together.
Oh ! I was hoping
you would say that.
-Yeah.
-(CHUCKLES)
FINLEY: Help me!
Somebody, save me!
(GRUNTING)
THEODORA:
That poor little creature.
Wizard,
we must save him.
Somebody, help me.
Oh, no, no, no.
Allow the Wizard.
FINLEY: Help me!
Come on !
Of course I'll save this
little talking monkey
in a bellhop's uniform.
You, mister!
Please, hurry up.
Do you have anything sharp?
Like a knife or something.
How about your teeth?
What kind of teeth you got?
OZ: (CHUCKLES) Calm down,
it's gonna be all right.
You gotta get me
out of these vines.
Calm down.
I'm gonna die.
It's gonna eat me.
Don't worry. These vines
aren't gonna eat you.
Not the vines, the lion !
(LION SNARLING)
-Lion?
-(ROARS)
FINLEY: We're gonna die.
-We're gonna die!
-(SCREAMING)
Eat him first!
Zim Zallah Bim !
Be gone, coward !
Fear my greatness!
-You were wonderful, Wizard.
-(SCOFFS)
"Wizard"?
You mean
the prophecy was true?
Indeed.
All right, well,
I've saved the day.
It was nothing, just a little
prestidigitatic display.
-Shall we to the palace?
-Oh ! Yes.
Good day, sir.
Wait, please, sir.
My name is Finley.
My master's home was ransacked
by the Wicked Witch's baboons.
And I've been hiding
in these woods ever since.
But now you've saved
my life, oh, Wizard.
So I hereby swear
a life debt to you.
No. . . No need.
From this moment on I shall be your
loyal and faithful servant until death.
Well, he is cute.
All right, you're hired.
Wonderful.
Let's shake on it.
My bag, monkey.
Surely.
You must travel light.
(CRASHING)
I got it.
(FINLEY GRUNTING)
You two run along.
THEODORA:
It's the Emerald City.
Just down this hill,
along the Yellow Brick Road.
OZ: Wow.
It'll all be yours now.
It's a good thing
green is my favorite color.
(THEODORA LAUGHS)
You are going to make the
best king Oz has ever known.
Thank you.
And I will be so proud
to be your queen.
My queen?
We'll spend
a lifetime together.
But right now, there's
thousands of people in Oz
waiting to witness
your miracles. (CHUCKLES)
Thousands?
That's a big show.
(FINLEY GRUNTING)
Phew!
What now, Wizard?
Monkey, tell me again
about that life debt.
-I devote my life to you.
-Mmm-hmm.
Whatever you wish,
whatever you want.
It is my sworn duty
to deliver for you
-until the end of my days.
-Mmm-hmm.
And there's
no getting out of it?
None, sir.
It is irrevocable.
Good.
Because I'm not the Wizard.
(FINLEY LAUGHS)
Oh, sir, your sense of humor
is as boundless as it is wondrous.
-You remind me. . .
-Monkey.
I'm not the Wizard.
Well, you could have told me
before I sealed the life debt.
It's too late.
You got to come clean
for that innocent young girl.
I'll deal with her later.
As my new assistant
all you need to know are the three "ups".
Show up, keep up, shut up.
But. . .
What's the third "up"?
Right. Now, listen,
I'm depending on you.
We need to convince
the good people of Oz
that they've found
their wizard.
(FANFARE PLAYING)
(HUFFS)
THEODORA: Hello, Knuck.
Theodora, we've been
expecting you.
I shall blow a fanfare.
(BLOWING TRUMPET)
No, no, no, no.
No. Not now.
(KNUCK GRUNTS)
This is the Wizard.
How do you do, sir?
-This is the Wizard?
-(THEODORA GIGGLES)
Is there a problem?
Yeah.
(SOLDIERS GRUNTING)
-LEADER: Halt.
-(GUARDS VOCALIZE)
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
All hail the Wizard.
WINKIE GUARDS:
The mightiest of mighties.
The greatest, most powerful
and most genuine
of real and true wizards.
Thank you.
A wizard above scrutiny
with no covert agenda
or subversive intention
whatsoever.
-Okay.
-A wizard of the highest moral rectitude.
He's just a real, good,
solid wizard, everyone.
The Wizard, here he is.
How'd I do?
(HORSES WHINNYING)
LEADER: Forward, march !
FINLEY: (STAMMERING)
Hello? Guys?
Can I get in the carriage?
Can I please
get in the carriage?
(STRAINING)
-I shall blow a fanfare.
-THEODORA: Not now.
(KNUCK GRUNTS)
Is that it? Is that my throne?
Do you like it?
I do so hope you like it,
because I've been personally watching
over it awaiting your arrival.
OZ: Oh. . .
Much obliged.
Praise be you are here
at last
and the prophecy
shall be fulfilled.
Oh, this is a glorious day
for us all.
And may I add, you're as
handsome a king as we've ever had.
(CHUCKLES) Flatterer.
Who is this fetching woman?
This is my sister.
I am Evanora,
the royal advisor.
I have been protecting the Emerald City
whilst we awaited your arrival.
I am here to serve
you as I served the king before you.
Well, I look forward
to being served.
Oh, sister,
I like him already.
Oh. . . My scepter.
EVANORA: Oh, yes,
go on then, have a seat.
How does it feel?
Fits like a glove.
Goodness.
Knuck will show you to your chambers
and then we can, uh. . .
(WHISPERING)
We can chat more later.
Can't wait. Monkey, my bag.
Yes, Wizard, right away,
oh, great and powerful one.
(KNUCK GRUNTING)
-Thank you, sourpuss.
-Whoa! (GRUNTS)
My name is Knuck!
Isn't he wonderful?
Didn't I say he would come?
You dare escort
that oaf in here
and allow him to climb
on the hallowed throne?
And why not?
He is the Wizard.
"The Wizard." Or so he says.
Did it not occur to you
that he might be an imposter in
league with the Wicked Witch
and sent here to kill us?
The Wicked Witch?
Don't be ridiculous.
(SCOFFS) I'm not the one
who's underestimating her cleverness.
Or maybe it's you
I'm underestimating.
Have you finally
joined her side, sister?
I am on no one's side.
You know that.
I simply want peace.
It's all I ever wanted,
and the Wizard can do that.
He's a good man.
What do you know
about goodness?
Deep down, you are wicked.
I am not wicked !
(THEODORA GASPS)
That temper
really is wasted on you.
Do you honestly think
that I could conspire
against you with her?
You are my sister
and I love you.
All right.
But I do need proof that
he is who he claims to be.
But he has already
proven himself.
Not to me, he hasn't.
OZ: Thank you for the tour.
It's my job.
Giving tours?
Taking care of the king.
(LAUGHS) Of course.
And on that note
I was thinking it might be
nice to have a royal feast.
Maybe a grand roast.
You know, my sister has been telling me
that your magic is really quite powerful.
Oh, really?
Yes, uh, boggling to the minds
of all who witness it.
Oh, I do wish I could
see it for myself.
-Yes.
-(GASPS)
Why not show me now?
-Now?
-Here.
All things in good time.
And a good time
for all things. (CHUCKLES)
So wise. So true.
Well, um,
there is one last room
that I would like you to see.
The royal treasure of Oz.
It belongs
to whoever is king.
(SIGHS HEAVILY)
It's all right, Wizard.
Go and enjoy your riches.
(OZ LAUGHING)
It's mine!
Mine!
Oh, no more second-hand suits
for you, baby!
Nothing but
the silks and satins!
Ali Baba!
(LAUGHING)
And one of these things!
What is this?
-A chalice.
-A chalice!
I've always wanted a chalice.
And now I've got one.
Well, uh, not quite yet.
You see,
you only become the king
after you defeat
the Wicked Witch.
That's the prophecy.
And since you haven't
done that yet, you're not. . .
-I'm not actually king.
-Not yet, no.
You still have to
get rid of the Wicked Witch.
Right.
And killing her
won't be easy.
No, I don't
suppose it will be.
Mmm.
Wait a minute.
No one said anything
about killing anybody.
Oh. Well, if you're not interested in
being king that's all right with me.
We can just forget about
the whole thing.
The gold and the rubies,
the chalice.
I'm interested !
I'm just not too keen
on killing a lady.
She's not a lady.
She's a wicked witch.
And your magic is the only
thing strong enough to destroy her.
All you have to do is journey
to the Dark Forest
and destroy her wand.
-Her wand.
-Yes.
It's the source of
all her power.
Without it, she dies.
I haven't even said
goodbye to Theodora. She will be upset.
I will talk to her
in the morning.
I will tell her
how much you love her. . .
No.
No, don't. . .
Don't say anything.
All right. I will say whatever
it is you want me to say
but are you going to
save us all or not?
I'm your wizard.
FINLEY: We're really
gonna do this?
How hard could it be
to kill a wicked witch?
Hard. Really hard.
It's very, very hard
to kill a wicked witch.
And what about that
poor girl back there?
I think she really liked you.
She'll get over me.
They always do.
She's a pretty young witch.
There'll be plenty
of wizards knocking at her door.
Oh, every lie you tell gets us one step
closer to the Emerald City dungeon.
Then don't think
of them as lies.
Think of them as stepping
stones on the road to greatness.
Wait, I got it.
We'll turn around and go back.
You'll come clean.
You apologize for lying
about being the Wizard
and for lying
to that poor girl. Okay?
You gotta really
seem contrite. You gotta sell it.
Maybe you could even cry.
Can you cry? I could cut up an onion.
We're not going back.
We're gonna find
this wicked witch,
steal her wand,
I'll get that
big pile of gold
and you can have a nice
pile of bananas, all right?
Bananas.
Oh, I see.
Because I'm a monkey,
I must love bananas, right?
That is a vicious stereotype.
-You don't like bananas?
-Of course I love bananas.
I'm a monkey,
don't be ridiculous.
I just don't like
you saying it.
How about this?
We offer to wash all the
windows in the Emerald City
-for an entire year.
-Uh-huh.
FINLEY:
They'd have to forgive us.
Or we could give them
a little help with their infrastructure.
I noticed some yellow
brick potholes back there.
That looks bad.
We're not going down there.
Someone might need our help.
Not that you care.
Get back here!
You get back here!
We gotta get the Wicked Witch.
What are we doing over here?
What happened here?
(CRUNCHING)
(WIND WHISTLING)
-(GIRL SOBBING)
-(GASPING)
(SOBBING CONTINUES)
Hello?
-Hey, there.
-(GASPS)
-Are you all right?
-(SNIFFLING)
Don't worry,
we're not gonna hurt you.
This is Finley.
Hi.
My name is Oz.
GIRL: Are you. . .
Are you the Wizard?
Oh, you. . .
You've heard of me.
Everyone has.
Good. Then you know there's
nothing to be afraid of.
So, just come on
out of there.
But I can't.
Oh. All right, hold on.
Get this off of you.
Oh, no.
(SNIFFLING)
I'll never get back together.
Don't worry.
I think I have something.
Give me that bag.
I, uh, packed something. . .
There it is.
CHINA GIRL:
What is that?
Magic in a bottle.
Magic?
Let's give it a try.
All right.
Just give it a little dab.
Like so.
Okay.
Should work.
There we go.
Ta-da!
(RUMBLING)
Oh, no, no, no!
(FINLEY GASPING)
They're coming back!
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
It's okay.
(SNIFFLING)
(SOBBING)
They're gone.
-The Wicked Witch sent them.
-Why?
Last night,
the whole town was celebrating
out in the streets
because we had heard
that you finally arrived.
Me?
Everyone was so happy.
But then. . .
But then those things flew in.
And then. . .
And then they. . .
(SOBBING)
Here we go.
Last piece.
Would you like to
try to stand?
There.
All right.
There we go.
Easy.
Okay.
-I'm gonna let you go.
-Oh !
Okay.
Now walk to me.
I don't think I can.
I think you can.
Come on.
(LAUGHING) All right.
You did it.
Thank you.
(FINLEY SNIFFLES)
"Dark Forest."
All right, this is it.
Just head on down that way,
about two, three hours.
You'll hit the Emerald City.
Tell them I sent you,
they'll take great care of you.
Nice meeting you.
But,
I wanna go with you.
What?
Aw ...
On a witch hunt?
No, you're just
a little girl.
I'm not as delicate
as I look!
That didn't hurt.
I'm coming with you.
Listen, we have one rule
in show business.
Never work with
kids or animals.
And I'm already working
with this thing.
-(GROWLS)
-Relax.
The answer's no.
(SNIFFLING)
Oh, no, no, no.
Don't. . .
Don't do that.
You're fine.
(SOBBING)
You're gonna leave me alone.
Look, you're. . .
You're fine.
On a road in the
middle of nowhere?
All you have to do
is take the Yellow Brick Road.
You'll get there.
(SOBBING HYSTERICALLY)
It's crying again,
what do I do?
(CHINA GIRL WAILING)
Oh, no.
Off. Come on. Off.
Off of there!
Scat! Get off!
Please let me
come with you.
No! Get off of there!
I promise
I won't bother you !
No dolls
on the witch hunt!
(CONTINUES SOBBING)
-Please, let me come!
-Fine.
Fine!
If you wanna come, come.
We'll all go,
it'll be a big party.
Great. Let's go
kill ourselves a witch !
(HUMMING CHEERFULLY)
(BRANCHES CREAKING)
(CROWS CAWING)
CROWS: You'll die,
you'll die, you'll die!
Did those crows just say
that we were gonna die?
They did.
CHINA GIRL: Wizard?
(OZ GRUNTS)
Come on.
CHINA GIRL: I'm scared.
(OWL HOOTING)
Think there are
ghosts out here?
No. Of course not.
Evil spirits maybe?
The undead?
(WHIMPERING)
Will you stop that?
(CHINA GIRL GASPS)
(FINLEY SCREECHING)
No. Get off!
Something's got my tail.
Something's got my tail !
Will you calm down?
(ALL SCREAMING)
(SNARLING)
No! What is it?
-CHINA GIRL: Look out!
-I wanna go home!
I wanna go home!
-Hey!
-Hat!
Thanks.
CHINA GIRL: Look out!
-OZ: Come on.
-(FINLEY YELLING)
(GROWLING)
OZ: Hate the Dark Forest.
Hate the Dark Forest.
CHINA GIRL: (PANTING)
Oh, my gosh. That was close.
Where are we?
OZ: This must be the place.
So, how are you gonna
kill the Wicked Witch?
All I need to do is
get her magic wand.
Once I destroy that,
she's finished.
Why don't you
just use this?
-It's got a knife!
-Where'd you get that?
I'm made of china.
I gotta protect
myself somehow.
Give me that.
-Hey!
-(KNIFE CLATTERING)
-Honestly.
-"Honestly" yourself.
(GASPS) Look.
CHINA GIRL:
That must be her.
Come on.
OZ: (WHISPERING)
She put down the wand.
But how are we gonna get it?
Hey!
(WHISPERING) Now, listen up.
Here's the plan.
The Wicked Witch
is the triangle.
Monkey, you're the X.
I'm the O.
China Girl,
you're the squiggly line.
I wanna be a heart.
Can I be a heart?
All right, fine.
You're a heart.
Okay, now,
heart stays here
as O makes his way over here.
X counters thusly.
Clear so far?
(SNEEZES)
(SNIFFLES)
Bless you.
Good work. You just
sneezed away the plan.
-Sorry.
-Never mind.
Just go over there and make
some of your animal noises.
I'll grab the wand
when she's not looking.
Get out of here.
(QUIETLY)
Yes! Come on, come on.
(CHAINS ON GATE RATTLING)
(GATE CREAKING)
Oh, no!
(GASPING)
FINLEY: Moo!
Moo!
A cow?
FINLEY: Moo!
(WHISPERING)
Come on. Come on.
-Hurry!
-I got it!
-Break it.
-Break it, Wizard.
-All right.
-Break it!
WOMAN: Did you say "Wizard"?
(ALL SCREAMING)
No!
WOMAN: Are you
really the Wizard?
Um. . . That's
a complicated question.
I mean, what is a wizard? I. . .
Um. . .
Yes.
I'm the Wizard.
Then there's hope.
What's going on?
Not sure.
I sneezed the plan away.
I have waited so long
to meet you.
So, we've never met?
Certainly not.
I'd remember
a thing like that.
You've never been to Kansas?
What is Kansas?
Is that where you're from?
My, you must have
traveled very far to get to the Land of Oz.
I did.
I'm Glinda the Good.
The Witch of the South.
I thought Evanora
was the Good Witch.
Evanora is
the true Wicked Witch.
Conniving and as cruel
as they come.
She's fooled most everyone,
including her own sister.
She made everyone believe
that I poisoned my father
-but it was her.
-CHINA GIRL: Then,
she's the one who
destroyed my village?
I'm so sorry, child.
FINLEY: Here's your wand.
Sorry I mooed.
And to think,
you almost killed Glinda for a bit of gold.
OZ: A bit?
There were
mountains of it, buddy.
Not that I was
going to do it.
I wasn't really going
to break your wand.
Follow me.
Okay.
EVANORA: No.
No, no, no, no, no.
It cannot be.
Curse you, Glinda.
You should be dead.
I'll see you dead yet.
Curse you and
your pretty little face.
-(DOOR OPENS)
-THEODORA: Sister.
Sister, the Wizard is missing.
I've looked everywhere,
but he's gone.
What is it?
Where is the Wizard?
(CLEARS THROAT)
Where's the Wizard?
With Glinda.
(SIGHS)
Then it's happening.
Oh, sister, he's fulfilling
the prophecy.
He'll bring her darkness
to the light and peace to the land.
Yes, I'm certain that's what
is happening. It must be.
Where did you get that?
This?
Oh.
It was a gift. From him.
He came to my chambers
last night.
Oh, how we danced.
-For hours, it seemed.
-(QUIET MUSIC PLAYING)
Oh, I can still feel his body
pressed against mine.
Oh, sister, you were
right about him.
He is the great Wizard.
He must be, to make me
feel the way I feel.
Oh, no.
Not you, too, sister?
He said we would
rule Oz together.
He said I would be his queen.
Did he?
Are you quite sure it wasn't
you who said it to him?
(SOBBING)
You fool !
(WAILING)
Serves you right.
(SCREAMS)
I want Glinda and that wizard
torn to shreds.
Do not fail me a second time.
(YELLING) Fly!
(GUARDS GRUNTING)
GLINDA: On the day my father died,
we lost a kind and noble leader.
And a dark shadow
was cast across this land.
I've had to stand alone
against Evanora and watch
as towns were destroyed,
children were orphaned
and my heart was broken.
I've been unable to protect
the good people of Oz by myself.
With only faith in my father's
prophecy, I've waited.
For you,
great Wizard from Kansas,
to come and set things right.
Oh.
So, that's the prophecy.
Um. . .
Well, you see,
when I agreed to be king,
I didn't realize how
complicated all of this was.
She knows.
What?
Evanora knows you know
the truth now. Look.
CHINA GIRL: Oh, no.
Uh. . .
What do we do?
Wizard, now is the time.
The time?
Use your magic.
Oh. . .
My magic. Yes. Uh. . .
(YELLING)
I think we should run.
Run?
Yeah.
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
You heard the Wizard. Run !
CHINA GIRL:
Let's get out of here!
OZ: Let's go!
(OZ WHIMPERING)
They're gaining on us!
(STAMMERING)
What are you doing?
Is. . . Is that gonna stop them?
I don't know.
(GUARDS GRUNTING)
Nice work. We lost them.
Phew! That was close.
Yeah.
Wait, I hear something.
(ROARING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
CHINA GIRL:
They're getting closer!
OZ: Wait for me!
(OZ GRUNTING)
Look out!
(VOICE ECHOING) Monkey!
Little China Girl !
CHINA GIRL:
Wizard ! I'm over here!
-(GRUNTS)
-(CHINA GIRL SCREAMING)
-Help! Catch me, please!
-Got you !
(OZ GRUNTS)
-Are you all right?
-Yes.
I'm okay, too.
(BABOONS SCREECHING)
Just go!
Great! A bunch of fog.
This is her big idea
on how to save us?
Well, it was the best I could
do under the circumstances.
Uh. . .
(ALL PANTING)
OZ: Oh, okay.
Whoa!
Catch her!
Get me! Don't let go!
CHINA GIRL:
Monkey, grab her!
OZ: Don't let go!
Don't let go!
FINLEY: Pull my tail. Ow!
Not so hard.
(ALL STRAINING)
CHINA GIRL:
They're getting closer!
OZ: What do we do?
What do we do?
Just do what I do.
-Unless you've got something.
-Uh. . .
No, you go.
Wait. What are you doing?
Wanda!
Where are you going?
She said to do what she did.
Just because she jumped off
the cliff, you're gonna jump off the cliff?
I have wings.
-What about me?
-CHINA GIRL: Come on !
Um. . .
(SCREAMING)
(BUBBLING SOUNDS)
Whee!
Whoa! Oh ! Oh !
Whoa!
(GIGGLES)
Wow.
Whoa!
Oh ! Oh, oh, oh !
These things go
kind of fast, huh?
(GIGGLING)
Hey, is. . . Is that a wall?
GLINDA: Of sorts.
It repels our enemies
and protects us from harm.
But we're
headed straight for it.
GLINDA: Yes, we are.
And going very fast.
How do you, uh. . .
Does this thing
have any brakes? Uh. . .
I'm going too fast!
I'm gonna die!
GLINDA: You needn't
worry, Wizard.
It's a magic wall.
And all good-hearted souls
get to pass through.
I'm gonna die!
(OZ YELLING)
Wanda!
Oh !
CHINA GIRL: It's beautiful.
(PEOPLE SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
They've waited a long time
for you, Wizard.
(SHOUTING EXCITEDLY)
(CROWD CHEERING)
All hail the great
and powerful Oz!
ALL: Hail !
Thank you !
Wow, you're a wonderful crowd.
You put the "merry" back in
"the merry Land of Oz."
(LAUGHS)
(CHEERING)
Hi, what's your name?
-You're very beautiful.
-Oh, thank you.
Girls, listen,
I am not a toy. I am not a toy!
-(KISSING)
-Oz! Oz!
-Hello!
-(CHEERING)
What? No fireworks?
What are fireworks?
Remind me to
show you sometime.
Glinda, I didn't know
if you'd like these, or these.
They're both so beautiful,
I couldn't possibly decide.
MAN: We need
your help, Wizard.
WOMAN: Please save us!
You know,
I should tell you, um. . .
I might not actually
be a wizard.
Yes, I know.
Oh.
At least, not any kind of wizard
we were expecting.
You could tell?
Yes.
I can also tell
you're weak, selfish,
slightly egotistical
and a fibber.
I see.
Anything you don't know about me?
Whether or not
you'll save my people.
No. I just told you
I'm not the Wizard.
But they don't know that.
If you can make them believe,
then you're wizard enough.
These are desperate times,
after all.
Can you make them believe?
Will I still get that gold?
Uh-huh.
Good people of Oz.
Your Wizard is here!
(ALL CHEERING)
What's the matter, sister?
THEODORA:
Look at how happy they are.
Do you think
she'll be his queen?
EVANORA: Well,
of course she'll be his queen.
-What did you expect?
-(SIGHS)
You can't compete
with Glinda's charms.
No one can.
Oh, God. Sister, it hurts.
Such is a broken heart.
Your precious wizard
did that to you.
Make it stop.
Would you like me to?
One bite is all it takes.
One bite and your world
will change forever.
One bite and your heart
will become impenetrable.
One bite and you and I
will finally share the throne.
Unless you'd rather see
Oz and Glinda there.
(VOICES WHISPERING)
(GASPS)
You're the wicked one.
Not Glinda.
Sister, you lied to me.
It's nice, isn't it?
How clear everything becomes.
(GASPING)
(GROANING)
(SHRIEKING)
(GASPING)
What is happening to me?
Oh, it's just your heart
withering away.
Fear not, Theodora, for soon you will
feel nothing at all except
beautiful wickedness.
(GROANING)
(SCREAMING)
(DISTORTED LAUGH)
Sister?
(GASPING)
Oh, sister, you're hideous.
(THEODORA GROANS)
I can cast
a simple enchantment
and have you looking
just the way you were before.
No!
This is who I am now.
I want him to
see me like this.
I want him to know that he was the one
who made me this way.
(CACKLING)
Oh, dear.
It's imperative that you behave like
the great leader that they think you are.
Morale is essential if we have
any hope of defeating Evanora.
-And I assume you have a plan.
-No.
You have a plan.
You're going to lead us into battle
and take back the throne.
And do we have
an army to help do this?
Of sorts.
The Quadlings, Your Highness.
You're soldiers?
No, sir. Farmers, mostly.
Farmers?
But you can fight.
No, sir.
Many of us can hoe.
Oh, you can hoe.
-And I can work with iron.
-That's good.
-I bake bread.
-Yummy.
-I can sew.
-Not so helpful.
I can make a scarecrow.
Ah !
Well, that'll come in handy.
-It might.
-Hmm.
And these are the Tinkers.
(TINKERS GRUNT)
Are you kidding me?
We're tougher
than we look, Wizard.
(TINKERS CHEER)
What they lack in stamina
the Tinkers make up for in ingenuity.
They can build anything.
(TINKERS CHEER)
OLD TINKER: And I'll
tell you what else.
We can build anything.
Yeah, I got it.
And we're prepared
to storm the Emerald City.
(TINKERS CHEER)
If you don't keel over
on the way there.
Ow!
And, finally, the Munchkins.
(UPBEAT FANFARE PLAYING)
Please tell me,
you gentlemen can fight.
No.
But we make pretty clothes.
Also, we sing.
Uh, no,
that won't be necessary.
I like it,
I think it's cute. I hope you like it.
(SINGING) The prophecy was clear
The wind would
bring you here
And so it was
A man named Oz
Would magically appear
All right, enough.
So, sound the battle call
The Wicked Witch will fall
And so it is
the wondrous Wiz
Will come
to save us all
All right, that's enough !
Munchkins, stop!
(SINGING STOPS)
(OZ SIGHS)
-They do make beautiful clothes.
-All right.
Now, listen, Wanda.
Glinda.
Guys, um, take five.
Uh, Glinda, these are all
very lovely people.
But do you honestly believe
that they can kill a wicked witch
and an army of flying baboons?
I don't expect them
to kill anyone.
What do you mean?
I mean the good people of Oz
are forbidden to kill.
Forbidden to. . .
You want me to lead
an army that can't kill?
If this was easy,
we wouldn't need a wizard, would we?
WOMAN 1 : Something's wrong !
-Look!
-WOMAN 2: What is that?
-MAN 1 : The wall !
-WOMAN 3: What's happening?
The Wicked Witch isn't
powerful enough to get through the wall.
OZ: It looks like
she's managing.
Not by herself,
she isn't.
What does that mean?
Is someone helping her?
Everyone, take cover!
Run quickly! Take cover!
(ALL CLAMORING)
Get the children to safety!
Run !
Glinda!
(PANICKED SCREAMING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
-(SCREECHES)
-(CROWD SHRIEKS)
-(SNARLS)
-(SCREAMS)
(SNIFFING)
There's so much good here.
It sickens me.
Ah !
Still think your Wizard
can save you from the likes of me?
(GROWLS)
Speak up, or I will
tear out your tongue!
Now, who is that?
Don't you recognize me,
Wizard?
Have I changed so much?
Theodora?
May I have this dance?
Huh? (GASPS)
Hey, hey!
(GRUNTS)
I get it!
You're a little upset!
-(GRUNTS)
-(YELLING)
Theodora, stop.
You're hurting him.
-(GRUNTS)
-(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANING)
Theodora,
what happened to you?
You happened to me.
This isn't you.
It's your sister.
She's worked her magic on you.
I'd hoped you'd be able
to see through her.
Oh, Glinda, so naive.
Just like your father.
That's why it was so easy
for my sister to kill him.
She only killed a man,
not what he believed in.
Begone, Witch, before
the Wizard makes mush of you !
(CROWD AGREEING)
Oh.
How sweet.
You all believe in him.
Well, so did I, once.
And as for you
my pretty one.
When I return with
my sister and her army
the Yellow Brick Road
will be red with the blood
of every Tinker, farmer and
Munchkin in your kingdom.
You underestimate us,
Theodora.
We are a strong
and united people.
And now the Wizard
is here to lead us.
And as for your Wizard,
he will be the first to die.
And you will all see that he
is nothing but a deceitful,
selfish and extremely
mortal man.
Give me that!
It was a broom
that you wanted.
Wasn't it, Wizard?
(CHUCKLING)
(CACKLING)
(CROWD CLAMORING)
It's all right.
It's all right!
She's gone now.
Don't be frightened.
Now that
the Wizard is with us. . .
Wizard?
Leaving?
But you promised to help us.
Yeah, well, that was
before I knew what we were up against.
An army and yet another
wicked witch?
This one bent on destroying
everyone, especially me?
We can defeat them.
There must be something.
Something we
haven't thought of.
Something that
we're not seeing.
Something we're
just on the verge of.
Glinda.
You need a real wizard.
Better yet, a general.
But you're all I have.
So, you're not the wizard
I was expecting.
So, you don't have the powers
I thought you'd have.
But you're here.
There must be a reason.
Maybe you're capable
of more than you know.
Glinda, I wish
I had the answer.
But I'm just a con man.
I'm a carnival magician.
I'm just not the man
you want me to be.
CHINA GIRL:
Someone needs to tuck me in.
Yes, of course.
Allow me.
My papa used to do it.
I see.
Perhaps you'd prefer
the Wizard, then?
CHINA GIRL: Yes, please.
(CLEARS THROAT)
All right.
In you go.
-Here you are.
-Uh-uh.
Just a moment.
Bring forth the covers now.
Yes, ma'am.
Comfy?
All right. Goodnight.
Do you grant wishes?
Do I what?
Grant wishes.
The old wizard
could grant wishes.
Ah.
People would
travel to the Emerald City
and ask him for things.
And if they were
good and noble wishes,
he would grant them.
Is that right?
Do you know what I'd wish for?
Hmm. A pretty dress?
To have my family back.
I know.
I'm sorry.
I can't grant wishes.
I'm not that kind of wizard.
That's what I thought.
Um, you see, where I come
from there aren't any real wizards.
Although, there is one.
Thomas Alva Edison.
The Wizard of Menlo Park.
A truly great man.
-Did he grant wishes?
-No.
But he could look into
the future and make it real.
He created the electric light,
the phonograph.
He created a camera that
could take moving pictures.
Pictures that move?
Yeah. Can you imagine?
And all he had was a little
bit of wire and some glass.
With almost nothing,
he made the impossible real.
Is that the kind
of wizard you are?
(SIGHS)
It's the kind of wizard
I'd like to be.
Well, you are that kind.
I can tell.
(YAWNING)
I'd rather you grant wishes,
but that's a good wizard, too.
Goodnight, Wizard.
Glinda. I've got it.
What have you got?
I've got a way out
of this mess.
-What is this?
-A battle plan.
It's all in there.
Illusion, misdirect,
sleight of hand.
Look,
I know I'm not the wizard
that you were expecting
but I might just be
the wizard that you need.
You said you were
just a con man.
Precisely.
Nothing but a trickster?
Yes.
A terrible cheat?
The best there is.
The carnival magician's
going to put on a show.
I'll put on
the show of a lifetime.
The likes of which
the Land of Oz has never seen !
Magic, mystery,
prestidigitation !
It'll be
my greatest trick yet.
Tinkers, gather around !
MASTER TINKER: Quickly, now.
This is what you're
gonna build.
Where I come from,
this is called a praxinoscope.
Although, I've made
a few modifications.
It allows you to project
an image into space.
Impossible.
Nothing's impossible
if you put your mind to it.
-Bully.
-TINKERS: Bully!
These three roads
all lead to the Emerald City.
To the east are
the deadly poppy fields.
-We'll have to steer clear of them.
-OZ: Why is that?
One good whiff
and it's everlasting sleep.
And we're not exactly
a terrifying army when we're awake.
All right.
We'll steer clear.
Or maybe not.
In the conjuring business,
flash is always good.
Gives the audience
a little "wow".
You gentlemen will be
combining sulfur rock, nitrate of potash
and charcoal to create what is commonly
known as black powder.
-(FINLEY SCREECHES)
-TINKERS: Whoa!
GLINDA: Mr. Quimby,
we need 200 bales of hay
delivered to the main road
by noon.
Mr. Zim, have
the Quadling carts. . .
(SEWING MACHINES WHIRRING)
Looks good.
(CRACKLING)
EVANORA: My very own
Winkie Guards
soon you will be facing Glinda
and her army of weaklings.
And when they see
our towering might,
-they will run and flee for the hills and. . .
-No!
We shall not let them flee!
We shall show them no mercy!
(ALL CHEERING)
Now, I've added this
adjustable lens to your design
along with
a few other things.
Have a look.
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
Yes! Edison himself
would be proud.
(MACHINE POWERING DOWN)
Now, there's something else
I need you to do.
But I'd rather
you just keep it between us.
Yes?
Do you know how
to build a hot air balloon?
(PLAYING FANFARE)
This is all very impressive
but you still haven't
told me how you plan
to get this thing
into the Emerald City.
Relax. I know someone.
What do you mean
you know someone?
Hello, Wizard.
Well, well, well.
If it isn't old Sourpuss.
(SCOFFS) My name is Knuck!
Now, you two be
nice to each other.
-Let's move it, Wizard.
-Can you give me a break?
I'll break your nose!
Guess I'm up.
Time to do what I do, right?
Cue the con man.
Would you stop? A con man
couldn't have done all this.
You're much more than that.
Well, then, it looks like
I've got you fooled, too.
The only person you've
got fooled is yourself.
For protection.
Not that you need it.
Great people of Oz.
Today we fight
to free the land
from the villainy
of the Wicked Witches.
(CROWD CHEERING)
We are few
but we are mighty!
(CROWD CHEERING)
-Quadlings.
-(CHEERING)
-Tinkers.
-Bully!
-Munchkins.
-(HIGH-PITCHED CHEERING)
We face great odds,
but we are armed with our courage,
our hard work,
and most of all,
our faith in one another.
We have nothing to fear
as long as we believe.
For when we do believe
anything is possible!
(CROWD CHEERING WILDLY)
Onward !
(URGING HORSE)
GATEKEEPER: Halt!
Good day there,
fellow Winkie guardsman.
What is your business here?
Supplies for battle.
We bring supplies for battle.
GATEKEEPER: I was told
of no such delivery.
Where are your
papers of transit?
KNUCK: Why this delay?
Do you not recognize me?
I'm Knuck, the City Herald.
Sir, I'm just trying
to do my. . .
-What I meant was. . .
-Hmm?
Let them pass!
Let them pass.
EVANORA: What's this?
They dare march on us?
-Tear them apart!
-Fly!
(SCREECHING)
(CACKLING)
(LAUGHING EVILLY)
(ROARS)
It's a trick.
MAN: Pull !
Retreat! Retreat!
Curse you !
(CHEERING)
Oh, it's not over yet.
The fog is lifting !
Quadlings, fall back.
Into the woods!
MAN: Watch out!
-(GASPING)
-(SNARLING)
Ah !
(GRUNTING)
(GASPING)
Away with her.
(SNIFFING)
-(TWIG CRACKLES)
-Oh !
-Herald.
-Great Wizard.
Who's this?
Emerald City underground.
Unload the carriage.
Yes, sir. To the rear.
MAN: Let's go!
Let's go.
You two, get the trolley.
Everything's ready.
All we need now is you.
Yeah, come on.
I just have to do
one thing first.
There's no time.
-Get this carriage in position.
-DRIVER: Yes, sir.
Hurry!
I told Glinda
you would do this.
She said I was wrong
about you. I guess I wasn't.
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about
that thing the Tinker built.
-The balloon.
-What balloon?
(SIGHS)
OZ: That's my cue.
All right, you guys.
Just remember,
stick to the plan.
FINLEY: Stick to the plan?
The plan was you.
We're supposed to
stick to you.
You guys will do great.
So long.
KNUCK: Come back!
We can't do it alone.
-Wizard !
-Wizard, I don't know what to do!
(STRUGGLING)
(CROWD CLAMORING)
(GRUNTING)
EVANORA:
Citizens of Emerald City.
Witness what happens
when you defy me.
(CROWD SHOUTING)
Glinda did very well for
herself today, I'll admit.
Leave her alone!
Unchain her, you witch !
MAN 1 : We know the truth.
MAN 2: You poisoned the king !
Guards!
Get them under control.
The citizens of Emerald City
will not tolerate this!
We will not!
Silence!
(CLAMORING)
(SIGHS) Ooh. . .
What should I do now?
I'd get your sister
and fly out of here.
Really?
While you still can.
Well, I think I'm going to do
something quite different
and I'm going to do it,
ooh, very,
very slowly, because
I just can't take the sight
of that pretty, pretty face.
Ooh, I'm going to
wipe out your light
until there is nothing
left but my darkness.
I have been waiting
for this for a long time.
(GLINDA GROANING)
(GLINDA CONTINUES GROANING)
FINLEY: Oh, no.
He said it was going to be
his greatest trick yet.
Did he tell you
the trick was on us?
How predictable.
(GUARDS VOCALIZING)
(CHINA GIRL GRUNTING)
(GRUNTING)
I knew that buffoon of yours
couldn't be the Wizard.
(GROANING)
(CLAMORING)
(THEODORA CACKLING)
Out of my way!
Give up, Glinda.
Why do you continue
to resist?
Because I believe
in the Wizard.
So did I, once.
Behold !
Look!
Your Wizard !
Where is he going?
He's abandoning us.
How could he?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
-(GRUNTS)
-No!
(GASPING)
(CROWD SCREAMING)
No!
(SOBBING)
Aw!
Not so great and powerful
after all.
(HUSHED WHIMPERING)
(MUTED SOBBING)
GUARD: You, there! Move back!
(SNIFFLING)
(QUIET SOBBING)
Hey.
Hello, monkey.
Oz!
-I thought you were dead.
-Shh.
You were crying pretty hard.
Was that for me?
Oh, no. Some of the smoke
got in my eyes.
Oh. Right. (CHUCKLES)
Wow, you fooled everybody.
That was your
greatest trick yet.
That was just
the opening act.
EVANORA:
Let this be the final word.
Your prophecy is dead.
Like the king who spoke it
and the wizard who tried to fulfill it.
All dead.
It's showtime.
And they will be joined in
death by Glinda the Good.
Farewell.
Say hello to
your daddy for me.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
(GRUNTING)
The dreams of
the people live on.
(CROWD GASPING)
(CROWD SCREAMING)
(GASPING)
(ROARING)
Fear me not,
good people of Oz.
Fear me not.
For it is l,
the great and powerful
Wizard of Oz!
More tricks?
After everything.
How dare you defy us!
OZ: Dare?
How dare you,
wicked sisters?
No one defies Oz!
(CROWD CHEERING)
Guards. Destroy him.
Forward !
GUARD: Attack!
(CLAMORING)
-(ROARING)
-(SCREAMING)
(OZ LAUGHING)
Guards! Come back here
this instant!
-(BLOWING TRUMPET)
-(LAUGHING)
You thought you could kill me?
Me?
Thanks to you,
l have shed my mortal shell
and taken my
true ethereal form.
(QUIET RUMBLING)
l'm now more
powerful than ever.
l'm invincible!
Do you still doubt me?
Doubt you?
I defy you !
(YELLS)
(CROWD GASPS)
(GASPING)
(ROARING)
Beautifully done, sister.
Thank you.
FINLEY: Hurry.
You're taking too much time.
Hold.
They think they're winning.
Turn it back on.
What? Turn it back on !
Oh, we got a loose wire.
Oi !
(STAMMERING) Screw's stuck.
Hold on.
Use this.
-Got it.
-Right.
(CROWD GASPING)
(BREATHLESS GASP)
This can't be.
(OZ LAUGHING)
You cannot defeat me.
I'm immortal !
l am the great and powerful
Wizard of Oz!
(CHEERING)
Now witness and observe
as l unleash the stars!
Behold!
(INHALES SHARPLY)
(WHISTLING)
-(EXPLODING)
-(BOTH GASP)
(CROWD CLAMORING)
So, those are fireworks.
(GASPING)
He is the Wizard.
(GASPS)
We got Evanora.
She's on the run !
All right! We got one!
-Yeah !
-(LAUGHING)
Come back here,
you coward !
Glinda.
It's you.
And you said that
I was the weak one!
(WHIMPERS)
I may not be able to kill you.
-Now.
-Okay.
But I can kill
the one you love.
Higher.
I'm trying.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SCREAMS)
(GASPS)
(OZ LAUGHING)
(YELLS)
Ready! Fire!
(SHRIEKS)
OZ: Begone, Wicked Witch!
Begone!
I hate you.
Begone, forevermore!
(CHEERING)
The Witch is gone!
The Witch is gone! Yes!
-Whoo-hoo!
-Bully, bully!
I knew we could do it.
Right.
Theodora, l know
your wickedness
is not your doing
and should you ever again
find the goodness
within you
you are welcome to return.
Never!
(CACKLING)
GLINDA: Not so fast.
You and I aren't finished yet.
You have the throne, Glinda.
What more could you want?
You can't give me that.
You took what mattered
most to me.
My father.
I'll never again feel
the comfort of his kindness
but I'll settle for the
freedom of his people.
Of course, Glinda.
I think at the very least,
they deserve that.
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
What's the matter, Glinda?
Out of bubbles?
I don't need them.
Bubbles are just for show.
(BOTH STRAINING)
(GRUNTS)
(STRAINED BREATHING)
(GROANS)
What have you done?
(WHIMPERING)
(GRUNTING)
(SNARLING)
(GROWLING)
(GASPING)
Look what you've done to me!
Now everyone will see you
as you truly are.
(GROANS)
In the name of my father,
I banish you from the Emerald City
never to return.
(SCREECHING)
(SCREAMING)
(GASPING)
(HISSING)
GLINDA: Good people of Oz,
I have here a missive
from the great Wizard himself.
"With little more
than pluck and belief,
"we made the
impossible happen.
"As your Wizard,
I hereby decree
"the Land of Oz
will forever be free."
(ALL CHEERING)
(TOLLING)
MASTER TINKER: Okay.
Close the curtains, please.
CHINA GIRL: I'm trying.
All right.
Let's give it a try.
-ls it on?
-(FEEDBACK WHINING)
ls this thing working?
CHINA GIRL: It's wonderful.
Well.
lf it isn't the most
beautiful witch in all of Oz.
Hi, Glinda.
Hello, Wizard.
Well done, Tinker.
Your machine
works beautifully.
That's just workmanship.
What you displayed
was real courage.
Your father would have been
more than proud.
He would have marveled
at the woman you've become.
Zim Zallah Bim !
Excellent work, everyone.
Now we're ready
in case anyone
wants to speak
with the Wizard.
Now, remember,
Oscar Diggs died
so that the
Wizard of Oz could live.
When those witches come back,
and they will come back,
we're going to need
everyone to believe.
Your secret's safe with us.
Good.
And now it's time
for some gifts.
Gifts?
-Gifts?
-(BLOWS FANFARE)
Knuck, not now.
What kind of gifts?
Well, you know
I can't grant wishes,
so this will have to do.
First, the Master Tinker.
To the man who can
make anything, my lucky
thingamajig.
May it assist you
in the reconstruction
of the Emerald City.
I will cherish this forever.
Thank you for
your faith in me.
And now for Sourpuss.
My name is Knuck!
Sourpuss,
I grant you something
you are in need of most.
Something that,
where I come from
can turn the saddest day
into a happy one.
-I don't want that.
-It is yours.
-Take it back.
-I cannot.
CHINA GIRL: Knuck,
you look nice with a smile.
(MASTER TINKER CHUCKLES)
You do look nice.
Thank you.
Finley, you stood
by my side
when any monkey
in his right mind would have flown away.
To you, I give something
that I've never given to anyone.
(BLOWS)
My friendship.
Now you're my partner.
You're my friend.
That's all
I ever really wanted.
My turn, my turn.
Come here.
I'm afraid I can't give
you what I know you want most of all.
All I can offer you is this.
It's us.
I know it's not the family
that you had in mind.
It's perfect.
Thank you.
I wonder what
you're gonna get.
Oh, I don't need
anything, child.
You better have
something for Glinda.
OZ: But of course.
I've saved the best for last.
For you,
a sight envied by all
and seen by none.
You'll be astounded
by what you find
behind the curtain.
Oh, my.
It's very tight in here.
It's nice, isn't it?
I know what
you're up to, Wizard.
What? I'm just
giving you a tour.
And I want to thank you.
For opening my eyes.
And what do you see?
That I have everything
I ever wanted.
For the record, I knew
you had it in you all along.
Greatness?
No. Better than that.
Goodness.
Now, Knuck.
(BLOWING FANFARE)
(MASTER TINKER CHUCKLES)
(GRAND MUSIC PLAYING)
(WHIMSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(GRAND WALTZ PLAYING)
(RHYTHMIC POP SONG PLAYING)
l've seen the light
in the sky
ln the skies like fireflies
Burning bright,
just to vanish in the dark
l've held hope
in my two hands
That there would be
another chance
To find a kingdom
l believe in in my heart
'Cause underneath the good there's
something greater than you know
When you're almost there
And you're almost home
Just open up
your eyes and go, go
When you're almost there
Almost home
Know you're not alone
You're almost home
When you run, run so far
You've forgotten who you are
Where you're from
lt's like some other universe
You count your steps
Like they're regrets
You catch one breath
Then lose the rest
Wrong is right
Right is left
And there's nowhere
left to turn
So don't believe in everything you
think, you think you know
When you're almost there
And you're almost home
Just open up
your eyes and go, go
When you're almost there
Almost home
Know you're not alone
You're almost home
When you let
your heart be the compass
You won't get lost
Not if you trust it
When you hear
the sound of the trumpet
Louder than ever before
Oh, when you're almost there
Almost home
Just open up
your eyes and go, go
'Cause you're almost there
Almost home
Know you're not alone
You're almost home